<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/stat386-projects/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/stat386-projects/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-09-20T10:10:07-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/stat386-projects/feed.xml</id><title type="html">My Stat 386 Blog</title><subtitle></subtitle><author><name>Noah Lawrence</name></author><entry><title type="html">First Post</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/stat386-projects/2022/09/08/first-post.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="First Post" /><published>2022-09-08T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2022-09-08T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/stat386-projects/2022/09/08/first-post</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/stat386-projects/2022/09/08/first-post.html">&lt;p&gt;One important skill for Data Scientists is the ability to convey data in a way that is useful for others.  Using tools such as RMarkdown will make creating reports for your data significantly easier.  One of the best tools included in RMarkdown is LaTeX (commonly seen as $\LaTeX$), which essentially creates mathematical equations as you would see them in material such as websites and textbooks.  Here, I will make a basic guide to start you on your way to learning LaTeX as well as resources to help you find answers to any questions you have.  It is important to note that I don’t know everything about LaTeX and if you find that I missed something, feel free to leave a comment below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most important things in LaTeX (pronounced lay-tech/tek) is the ability to inline mathematical functions.  For example two-thirds can be represented in Latex as &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;$\frac{2}{3}$&lt;/code&gt; or $\frac{2}{3}$.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Noah Lawrence</name></author><summary type="html">One important skill for Data Scientists is the ability to convey data in a way that is useful for others. Using tools such as RMarkdown will make creating reports for your data significantly easier. One of the best tools included in RMarkdown is LaTeX (commonly seen as $\LaTeX$), which essentially creates mathematical equations as you would see them in material such as websites and textbooks. Here, I will make a basic guide to start you on your way to learning LaTeX as well as resources to help you find answers to any questions you have. It is important to note that I don’t know everything about LaTeX and if you find that I missed something, feel free to leave a comment below.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/stat386-projects/assets/images/image5.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/stat386-projects/assets/images/image5.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>