<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/stat386-projects/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/stat386-projects/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-10-19T16:51:13-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/stat386-projects/feed.xml</id><title type="html">My Stat 386 Blog</title><subtitle></subtitle><author><name>Noah Lawrence</name></author><entry><title type="html">Webscraping Stock Market Data</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/stat386-projects/2022/10/18/webscraping-post.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Webscraping Stock Market Data" /><published>2022-10-18T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2022-10-18T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/stat386-projects/2022/10/18/webscraping-post</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/stat386-projects/2022/10/18/webscraping-post.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;introduction-to-api-use&quot;&gt;Introduction to API use&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;API (application programming interface) is a tool that is built into many web services that allow for applications to retrieve data from a server.  In the data science realm, this most often shows up as get requests, which are requests that pull information from the web server.  This is useful in obtaining the data used within web sites but are formatted in such a way that may make webscraping difficult or only a specific subset of the data is displayed on the website.  API’s are also useful in variable data, such as in the BYU app where it will call the API to figure out what your classes are and when they are.  This data will change on a semester basis but the underlying code doesn’t need to be changed that much because the application simply calls to the API created by BYU.  In this post, we will show how to use AlphaVantage’s API to pull stock data&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;obtaining-an-api-key&quot;&gt;Obtaining an API key&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to limit the number of requests and limit the data to authorized users, API will often require authentication using keys.  In the case of AlphaVantage, they offer free keys to anyone who signs up for the service.  That can be done &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.alphavantage.co/support/#api-key&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.  When you sign up, it will generate an API key that you can save to your file.  Please remember that these keys are sensitive and should not be shared with anyone.  Additionally, remember that one of the best ways to protect your key is to save it in another file and simply read the file from your program.  You should not hard code your API key into your code, especially in the case that you open source the code.  Once you obtain the API key, continue on to the next step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;calling-the-api&quot;&gt;Calling the API&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best place to start for API calls is the documentation.  When a company releases an API, it often comes with documentation for the API.  In the case of AlphaVantage, it is extremely simple.  It is structured like this: https://www.alphavantage.co/query?function=FUNCTION&amp;amp;symbol=SYMBOL&amp;amp;apikey=APIKEY.  First is the function keyword, which is included in the API documentation.  Some of these functions are specifically premium features but it is listed in the documentation regarding which are premium and which are not.  Following the function keyword is the SYMBOL keyword which is simply the stock ticker symbol, which can be easily searched on google.  Finally comes the APIKEY keyword which is where the API key is placed.  As mentioned before, &lt;b&gt;DO NOT&lt;/b&gt; include this key directly in your code.  Often times, you will read this value in to a variable and that variable can be passed using {} like so …&amp;amp;apikey={your_api_key_variable_here} which makes it easier to obscure your api key.  When all of these variables are put in place, the API will often return a JSON file with all of the data that you queried.  There are additional parameters that can be passed in but I will not cover them here.  I would refer to the documentation found at the end of this post.
&lt;img src=&quot;STAT_386/stat386-projects/assets/images/alpha_vantage.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;test-text&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;why-bother&quot;&gt;Why bother?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the quantity of publicly available data, we may often ask ourselves,”Why bother?” The answer to this is simple.  API’s will make it simple in obtaining the data from the source and avoid having to deal with the formatting of certain webpages and will often include more data than is displayed on the website.  For this reason, API’s will be extremely helpful in obtaining the most useful and up-to-date data.  Using data pulled using this API, I will create a follow up post that includes analysis of the data obtained from this API.  There, it will be useful to see the connection of API use and data analysis. Stay tuned for more!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;links&quot;&gt;Links&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.alphavantage.co/documentation/&quot;&gt;Alpha Vantage Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Noah Lawrence</name></author><summary type="html">Introduction to API use API (application programming interface) is a tool that is built into many web services that allow for applications to retrieve data from a server. In the data science realm, this most often shows up as get requests, which are requests that pull information from the web server. This is useful in obtaining the data used within web sites but are formatted in such a way that may make webscraping difficult or only a specific subset of the data is displayed on the website. API’s are also useful in variable data, such as in the BYU app where it will call the API to figure out what your classes are and when they are. This data will change on a semester basis but the underlying code doesn’t need to be changed that much because the application simply calls to the API created by BYU. In this post, we will show how to use AlphaVantage’s API to pull stock data</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/stat386-projects/assets/images/stockmarket.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/stat386-projects/assets/images/stockmarket.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">An Introduction to $\LaTeX$</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/stat386-projects/2022/09/20/first-post.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="An Introduction to $\LaTeX$" /><published>2022-09-20T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2022-09-20T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/stat386-projects/2022/09/20/first-post</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/stat386-projects/2022/09/20/first-post.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One important skill for Data Scientists is the ability to convey data in a way that is useful for others.  Using tools such as RMarkdown will make creating reports for your data significantly easier.  One of the best tools included in RMarkdown is LaTeX (commonly seen as $\LaTeX$ and pronounced lay-tech/tek), which essentially creates mathematical equations as you would see them in material such as websites and textbooks.  Many of the skills learned in this guide will directly translate to RMarkdown, as the syntax is largely the same. Here, I will make a basic guide to start you on your way to learning LaTeX as well as resources to help you find answers to any questions you have.  It is important to note that I don’t know everything about LaTeX and if you find that I missed something, feel free to leave a comment below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;installation&quot;&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are 2 good starting places for LaTeX on your computer.  First, is an online resource called Overleaf.  It is a free web-based LaTeX editor that can compile your LaTeX code into PDF format for easy reports.  The only downside, in my opinion, is the need to create an account because I don’t like having to make an account for every website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The alternative is to compile LaTeX on your local machine.  For Windows, the most common LaTeX typesetting system is MiKTeX, which comes with a TeX editor called TeXWorks.  For Macintosh, MacTeX is the typesetting system.  For Linux, TeXLive is the most common.  Additionally, there are a variety of editors for each of these platforms, including some that are multiplatform, that you can use to your needs and liking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note, this installation will take quite a while because there are such a large number of packages that are included in the base LaTeX installation.  After this installs, you should be able to open your LaTeX editor and begin typing in LaTeX.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more help on installing for Windows, go &lt;a href=&quot;https://miktex.org/howto/install-miktex&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
For help installing on Mac, go &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tug.org/mactex/index.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
For Linux, due to the variety of distributions, I will simply say, Google is your friend here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;basic-syntax&quot;&gt;Basic Syntax&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LaTeX is a powerful tool to format mathematical formulas in a way that is readable but that isn’t its only use.  It can also be used to format documents for reports that are readable and can even include images or charts from tools such as RStudio.  Many academic papers, especially within science and mathematics, are formatted with LaTeX so it is important to learn it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To create your first document, the following code will be helpful to create it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;\documentclass{article}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;\begin{document}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;First document. This is a simple example, with no&lt;/code&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;extra parameters or packages included.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;\end{document}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first part, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;\documentclass{article}&lt;/code&gt; defines the type of document you are creating.  This will call from templates installed on your computer already.  The second part combined with its closing tag is the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;\begin{document}&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;\end{document}&lt;/code&gt; is basically the content of your document.  Everything inside of these tags will be what shows up compiled into a PDF/other document format.  If any LaTeX code shows up outside of these tags, it will not appear within your document.  The following lines are plain text that will be included.  It is important to note that formatting is not included within this part and the fact that the content is on two lines doesn’t mean that it will appear that way on the document.  To create a new line, you will use the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;\\&lt;/code&gt; characters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most important things in LaTeX is the ability to inline mathematical functions.  For example two-thirds can be represented in Latex as &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;$\frac{2}{3}$&lt;/code&gt; or $\frac{2}{3}$.  The dollar signs represent inline math functions.  Everything between the two dollar signs will be converted to a mathematical equation, assuming no syntax errors.  Additionally, there is a math mode that simply uses 2 dollar signs instead of one as is much more useful for long equations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within LaTeX, there are additional functions that allow you greater formatting within your document.  For example, you can create equations using the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;\begin{equation}&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;\end{equation}&lt;/code&gt; which will push the equation to the middle of the page.  These are most often called environments and will have specific formatting such as the equation environment shown below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The PDF of the normal distribution is:
\begin{equation}
\frac{1}{\sigma \sqrt{2\pi}}e^{\frac{-1}{2}(\frac{x-\mu}{\sigma})^2}
\end{equation}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of these things will need to be included within the document tags to appear in your document.  Since this guide is not by any means exhaustive, I recommend that you try getting the environment setup on your computer and trying out LaTeX for yourself.  Whenever you run into an error, try checking the logs to see where the error was thrown and more often than not, it’s missing parenthesis or missing a closing tag for your environments.  When in doubt, Google for the specific error to determine the specific error.  I also recommend visiting Overleaf’s documentation and guide, as that will teach much more of the basics and will give you a better idea of the possibilities of LaTeX.  Go on and create your own $\LaTeX$ documents!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;further-help&quot;&gt;Further Help&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.latex-project.org/help/documentation/usrguide.pdf&quot;&gt;LaTeX Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://tex.stackexchange.com/&quot;&gt;Tex Stack Overflow&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://overleaf.com/&quot;&gt;Overleaf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.overleaf.com/learn&quot;&gt;Learn LaTeX on Overleaf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Noah Lawrence</name></author><summary type="html">Introduction One important skill for Data Scientists is the ability to convey data in a way that is useful for others. Using tools such as RMarkdown will make creating reports for your data significantly easier. One of the best tools included in RMarkdown is LaTeX (commonly seen as $\LaTeX$ and pronounced lay-tech/tek), which essentially creates mathematical equations as you would see them in material such as websites and textbooks. Many of the skills learned in this guide will directly translate to RMarkdown, as the syntax is largely the same. Here, I will make a basic guide to start you on your way to learning LaTeX as well as resources to help you find answers to any questions you have. It is important to note that I don’t know everything about LaTeX and if you find that I missed something, feel free to leave a comment below.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/stat386-projects/assets/images/LaTeX.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/stat386-projects/assets/images/LaTeX.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>